Guide to the George Yuzawa Papers TAM.442
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
- Series III: Oversize, Ephemera and Printed Materials, 1942-1999
  - Yuzawa, James T.: Scrapbook of Clippings re: World War II, 1944-1953 (Box 6)
- Series IV: Video and Audio, undated
  Series consists of a betamax video cassette recording and three long-playing (LP) albums recording lessons in English language conversation for Japanese speakers.
  - "Channel 28" (Betamax L-250 Video Cassette), undated (Box 7)
  - English Conversation in Six Weeks 1 by Obunsha's Educational Records (LP 33 1/2), undated (Box 7)
  - English Conversation in Six Weeks 2 by Obunsha's Educational Records (LP 33 1/2), undated (Box 7)
  - English Conversation in Six Weeks 3 by Obunsha's Educational Records (LP 33 1/2), undated (Box 7)
- Series V: Photographs and Artwork, circa 1900-2009, undated
  This series consists of eighty three black-and-white and color photographs, and two pieces of artwork, dating from circa 1900-2009 that document George Yuzawa's family history, experience before, during and after World War II, and activism and personal life beginning in the early 1970s. Includes early twentieth century studio portraits of George Yuzawa, Kimiko Hattori, and family, and other pre-war photographs; and wartime-era snapshots of Yuzawa in the United States Army, and with family and friends.
  Events Yuzawa participated in or observed from the 1970s to circa 2009 include late 1970s group portraits of Yuzawa with JAHFA members; a visit to the White House with First Lady Rosalyn Carter; 1982 "Day of Remembrance" activities in New York City; Ronald Reagan signing bill to pay reparations to Japanese-Americans incarcerated during World War II; and Yuzawa receiving the "Day of Remembrance" Proclamation at City Hall in 1992, the Governor's Award for Excellence from New York State Governor George Pataki, and the order of the Sacred Treasure, 5th Class in 1983. Includes two reproductions of photographs depicting Japanese Americans in concentration camps during World War II used to publicize an exhibit at Ellis Island, "America's Concentration Camps: Remembering the Japanese American Experience," and a photograph of the exhibit.
  Two pieces of artwork include one colored (woodblock?) print of a skier by K. Sakamoto signed and inscribed to Yusawa (which may refer to Yusawa's enjoyment of skiing), and one pen and ink sketch of a man (possibly George Yusawa) unsigned.
  - Family Photographs, circa 1900s-1940s, 1960s (Box Tamiment Shared A004)
  - Photographs, circa 1940-1949 (Box Tamiment Shared A004)
  - Photographs, circa 1970-1979 (Box Tamiment Shared A004)
  - Photographs, 1980-1989 (Box Tamiment Shared A004)
  - Photographs, circa 1990-2009, undated (Box Tamiment Shared A004)
  - James Tamasaburo Yuzawa, George, Mr. Kikuchi, Yosemite National Park California [Oversized], circa 1920
  - Artwork, undated (Box Tamiment Shared A004)